fastjet.com 2019-05-12

# 

The fastjet Privacy Policy applies to the personal data that fastjet collects and uses regarding all guests travelling on fastjet services, with fastjet Airlines Ltd, fastjet Zimbabwe Ltd and fastjet Mozambique Limitada (collectively known as the “Group”).

### **1 Applicability**

1.1 The fastjet Privacy Policy applies to the personal data that fastjet collects and uses regarding all guests travelling on fastjet services, with fastjet Airlines Ltd, fastjet Zimbabwe Ltd and fastjet Mozambique Limitada (collectively known as the “Group”).

### **1.1 General - Personal data we collect**

1.1.1 When we use the term “personal data” in our Privacy Policy, we mean information that relates to our guests and allows us to identify our guests, either directly or in combination with other information that we may hold. As a guest, your personal data may include for example your name, your postal address and contact details, or information relating to your flight booking or travel itinerary.

1.1.2 We collect some personal data from our guests, for example when you book a flight with us, use our website or our app, use our services or contact us. We may also receive your personal data from our suppliers who provide services to you on our behalf (for example when you provide feedback on our services), our partners when you purchase their travel related products or third parties who act on your behalf, for example travel agents or other parties who book a flight for you.

1.1.3 If you book a flight on behalf of someone else, you must have their consent to use their personal information.

### **2 Type of data fastjet collects**

2.1 We may collect and process the following categories of information about you.

(i)   **Your name, surname, contact details (email address, postal address, telephone number;** when you create an account on our website, when you book a flight, when you take part in our competitions or surveys.

(ii)  **Information about your flight bookings, if you require special assistance or if you have specific dietary or medical requirements;** when you book or manage your flight.

(iii)  **Information about your health, if you have a medical condition that may be affected by flying;** when you provide us with this information before you fly.

(iv)  **Information about other passengers in your booking, which will include providing data on the ages of any children travelling with you;** When you make a booking on behalf of other passenger. (You require permission from the other passengers before providing this data).

(v)  **Information about your transaction, including your payment card details;** when you purchase fastjet products or services.

(vi)  **Advance Passenger Information. This information includes your full name, your nationality, your date of birth, your gender (where required) - the number and type of your travel document (e.g. passport or ID), its expiry date and country of issue** ; when you check in for specific travel routes.

(vii)  **Information related to your flights and our services in connection with your flights;** when you take an fastjet flight; when you use our services at the airport.

(viii)  **Information about your purchases of our partners’ travel related products and services;** when you purchase such products or services.

(ix)  **Communications you exchange with us (for example, your emails, letters, calls);** when you contact fastjet or you are contacted by fastjet;

(x)  **Your comments and feedback;** when you reply to our requests for feedback or participate in our customer surveys;

(xi)  **Your posts and messages on social media directed to fastjet;** when you interact with us on social media;

(xii)  **Information about how you use our website or our mobile app** , such as your searches for flights; when you navigate on our website or when you use our mobile app.

### **3 How and why fastjet uses your personal data**

3.1.1 At fastjet we use guests’ personal data for the following purposes:

#### **3.1.1.1  ** **To manage your reservations and flight bookings, and provide services in connection with these:**

(i) We use your information to perform our services in relation to your flight booking and itinerary. We also use it to change your flight bookings if you request such changes.

#### **3.1.1.2  ** **To communicate with you and maintain an effective service relationship:**

(i) For operational and administration purposes we may need to contact you via email or phone. This includes sending your confirmation of bookings and payments, sending you details related to your travel itinerary, notifying you of disruption or changes, etc. These communications are not made for marketing or sales purposes, and you will continue to receive them even if you have opted out of receiving marketing related communications. We will also use your personal data if we contact you after you have sent us a request, filled in a web-form through our website or contacted us on social media.

#### **3.1.1.3  ** **To improve our online services and presence:**

(i) We may also collect information on how you use our website, which pages of our website you visit most, which flights you search for and what products you buy, in order to understand what your preferences and how you use our website. If you have agreed to receiving marketing communications, this information allows us to send you relevant messages that we think you may find of interest or relevance.  If you are in the process of making a booking under your account and you leave our website before your order has been placed, we may contact you in order to help you easily complete your booking.  

#### **3.1.1.4  ** **To inform you about fastjet news and offers that you may like.**

(i) If you have indicated that you would like to receive information of  our services, flights, company news and offers we may contact you with such marketing information. Please note that we will not share your contact details and other personal data with any partners or other companies for marketing purposes. Our marketing communications may relate to the following with whom we do not share your details:

·         Avis Car Rental

·         Hotels.com

·         Puma

·         Peermont

·         CCA (Content Connect Africa)

·         Impala

·         NMB

·         Pesapal

·         Econet

We will update the above list with any changes to the products and services available on our website.  You can also choose to opt out from receiving marketing communications at any time, by clicking on the relevant unsubscribe link at the bottom of any marketing related email you may receive from us.  You may also send an email to data.protection@fastjet.com with the header “Unsubscribe”.

#### **3.1.1.5  ** **To improve our services, fulfil our administrative purposes and protect our business interests.**

(i) The business purposes for which we will use your information include accounting, billing and audit, credit or other payment card verification, fraud screening, safety, security and legal purposes.

#### **3.1.1.6  ** **To comply with our legal obligations**

(ii) As an airline we are obliged, where required for legal reasons to provide your information to airport authorities, National Aviation Authorities or immigration control agencies.

### **4 Sensitive personal data**

4.1 Data protection laws recognise that certain types of personal information are more sensitive. This is known as 'sensitive' or 'special category' personal information.

4.2 This type information will only be collected when you have given your explicit consent, or it is where necessary to do so, so that we are able to comply with regulatory and legal requirements.

4.3 By providing any sensitive personal data you explicitly agree that we may collect and use it to provide our services and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

4.4 If you do not allow us to process any sensitive personal data, this may mean we are unable to provide all or parts of the services you have requested from us. In such circumstances you will not be entitled to cancel or obtain a refund of any services or products you have paid. 

### **5  Requesting access to your personal data**

5.1 You have a right to request access to the personal data that we hold about you. This could include booking information relating to flights you have taken with us.

5.2 If you have questions in relation to your personal data, please contact us at: [data.protection@fastjet.com](mailto:data.protection@fastjet.com).

### **6 Security of your personal data**

6.1 We take appropriate adminsitrative, technical and business measures to protect your personal data against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage.  

6.2 When you provide your personal data through our website or our mobile app, this information is transmitted across the internet securely using high-grade encryption.

6.3 As described in this Privacy Policy, we may in some instances disclose your personal data to third parties. Where fastjet discloses your personal data to a third party, we require that third party to have appropriate technical and organisational measures in place to protect your personal data; however in some instances we may be compelled by law to disclose your personal data to a third party, such as border or immigration control agencies, and have limited control over how it is protected by that party.

6.4 The information that you provide to us will be held in our systems, which are located on our premises or those of an appointed third party. We may also allow access to your information by other third parties who act for us for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy or for other purposes approved by you. Your personal data may be accessed by and processed outside the European Economic Area (the European Economic Area being the European Union and Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway, also referred to as the “EEA”) - including by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers or agents (this includes staff engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your booking, ground handlers, and the provision of support services). Where your personal data are transferred outside of the EEA, we require that appropriate safeguards are in place.

6.5 We use safeguards to ensure that your personal information is secure. We limit access to information on a need-to-know basis and take appropriate measures to ensure that our people are aware that such information is only used in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

6.6 We undertake regular reviews of who has access to information that we hold to ensure that your information is only accessible by appropriately trained staff.

6.7 Our online forms are always encrypted and our network is protected and routinely monitored.

6.8 We will only retain your personal data for as long as we need it in order to fulfil our purposes set out in this Privacy Policy or in order to comply with the law.

6.9 However, please be aware that there are always inherent risks in sending information by public networks or using public computers and we cannot 100% guarantee the security of data (including personal information) disclosed or transmitted over public networks.

### **7 Cookies**

7.1 We use cookies in our website or in our emails. Cookies are small pieces of information stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. They enable you to navigate on our website or app and allow us to provide features such as remembering aspects of your last flight search to make subsequent searches faster. You can delete cookies if you wish; while certain cookies are necessary for viewing and navigating on our website or app, most of the features will be still accessible without cookies.

7.2 For more information on how we use cookies and how you can remove them, read our _Cookie Policy_ found on our website.

### **8  Sharing your personal data**

8.1 Your personal data may be shared with other companies within our Group.

8.2 We may also share some of your personal data with, or obtain your personal data from, the following categories of third parties:

(i) Airports, government authorities, law enforcement bodies and regulators when this is necessary to get you to your destination or is required by law.

(ii) Travel agents or other companies through which you book your fastjet flights.

(iii) Suppliers providing services to us in order to help us run our business and improve our services and your customer experience. For example, ground handling and services for us to the airports to which we operate. We may also disclose your information to our contact centre or the companies who help us get your feedback on our services.

(iv) Payment processing companies; fastjet shares some of your personal data, which includes information about your method of payment and flight booking. In order to ensure the security of your transactions and prevent or detect fraudulent transactions, we may also share your information with our fraud screening partner.

(v) Our partners who offer travel related products and services on our website, promote offers or co-organise competitions on our website. From time to time, we make certain third party offers available through our website. If you choose to purchase products or services offered on our websites by third parties accept offers, or participate in a competition, some of your personal data, such as your contact details and your billing information, may be directly collected by or disclosed to that third party.  

(vi) Authorities, including the National Aviation Authority and Airport Authorities.

8.3 In addition to the parties listed above, we may disclose your personal data when this is required by the law of any jurisdiction to which fastjet may be subject.

8.4 Through our website we provide links to third party websites which are subject to separate Privacy Polices. Please be aware that this Privacy Policy does not apply to such websites and fastjet is not responsible for your information that third parties may collect through these websites.

### **9 Right to access and contact information**

9.1 You have a right to request access to the personal data that we hold about you. This could include booking information relating to services you have purchased from us.

9.2 You also have the right to ask us to erase your personal information, ask us to restrict our processing of your personal information or to object to our processing of your personal information.

9.3 If you wish to exercise these rights, please contact us providing copies of two separate identification documents which provide photo identification and confirm your address, to verify your identity. You can send the request and accompanying ID documentation to [data.protection@fastjet.com](mailto:data.protection@fastjet.com). We will respond within 1 month on receipt of your request and copies of your identification documents. We reserve the right to charge a reasonable fee if manifestly unfounded or excessive for the administrative costs of complying with the request.

9.4 We will also charge a reasonable fee if an individual requests further copies of their data following a request.

9.5 Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [data.protection@fastjet.com](mailto:data.protection@fastjet.com).

### **10 Updates to our privacy policy**

10.1 We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will update the Privacy Policy and we will publish on our website any new version of this Policy.
